roh.org.uk 2019-04-03

# Privacy — Royal Opera House

**1.       ****Introduction**

The Royal Opera House is committed to protecting your personal information. It’s your information, it’s personal, and we respect that. We also want to maintain the trust and confidence of every one of our audience members and supporters, as well as each visitor who uses the Royal Opera House website.

Our Privacy Notice gives you detailed information on when and why we collect your personal information, how we use it and how we keep it secure.

Aside from helping us deliver truly exceptional performances and events, the information you share with us means you’ll receive a more personalized and rewarding experience e.g. information about performances, exhibitions and new works that may interest you as well as a smoother ticket-buying process.

Registering with the Royal Opera House has many benefits, not least the opportunity to manage your personal information and receive information about our work. You can register with us at any time on our [registration page](http://www.roh.org.uk/register).

### Show more details

Royal Opera House Covent Garden Foundation (the 'Royal Opera House') is a charitable company limited by guarantee incorporated in England and Wales (Company number 480523) Charity Registered (Number 211775). The Royal Opera House is the data controller of your personal information.

Contact details for the Royal Opera House

Royal Opera House  
Bow Street  
Covent Garden  
London  
WC2E 9DD

By phone +44 (0)20 7240 1200 or you can message us via our website [www.roh.org.uk/contact](http://www.roh.org.uk/contact)

If you have questions regarding your information or its use, please contact our Data Protection Manager by email: [dpm@roh.org.uk](mailto:dpm@roh.org.uk) or by phone: +44 (0)20 7240 1200

Although it is not compulsory to provide all of the information listed below, should you choose not to, then the Royal Opera House may not be able to provide you with the full range of services that we have to offer.

2.      **How We Collect Your Personal Information**

Generally, we collect your information when you decide to interact with us. This could include purchasing tickets online, over the phone or in person or it could be where you sign up to receive emails from us. We also look at how our audience use our website, so that we can offer the best possible experience whether you’re booking tickets or just trying to find out more about our latest productions.

### Show more details

We collect information in a number of ways which are listed below:

1\. When you create an account at [www.roh.org.uk](http://www.roh.org.uk/). Your account allows you do the following:

  * Buy tickets, gift certificates or packages of tickets
  * Join as a member
  * Make a donation
  * Buy merchandise such as DVDs from our online shop
  * Make a booking at one of our restaurants or bars
  * Register for special interest lists e.g. student’s scheme, welcome performances, cinema, surveys and competitions
  * Download a free programme for a cinema screening

2\. Use the ROH or our restaurant’s website or our app to pre-order drinks or food.

3\. Contact us by phone to book tickets.

4\. Book tickets in person at the box office.

5\. Contact us by post, e.g. application forms for Friends and Access members.

6\. Visit our website: we use cookies to help make the experience of using our website better and to personalise the service you receive from us – this means we will remember your previous visits and track the pages on our website that you visit. For more information please see our [Cookie Policy](http://www.roh.org.uk/policies/cookie-usage). When you visit www.roh.org.uk the Royal Opera House’s web server automatically records your public internet protocol ('IP') address and also generates a log file.

7\. From time to time, we may also get data about you from third parties – please see the ‘How we may use your information’ section for more details. This could include other artistic venues where you have seen the Royal Opera House’s work or partners that we have run competitions with.

**3.       ****The Types of Information We Collect**

We only collect the information that’s necessary to carry out our business, provide the particular service you’ve requested and to keep you informed. There are occasions when you can choose not to give us certain information, but this for example, may limit the level of personalization we offer e.g. you may not get to hear about an event you would have loved to have attended.

### Show more details

The type of information we collect depends on where and when it is gathered:

Information we obtain directly from you:

When you create an account with us, register on our website or purchase tickets or other items from us online, by post or phone we need to collect information from you in order to provide the service you are requesting.  
We may collect:

  * Prefix and name
  * Gender
  * Email address
  * Date of Birth
  * Contact phone number(s)
  * Payment card details. Please note, we will not hold payment information for any longer than it takes to process your transaction.
  * Delivery address(s)
  * Billing address

If you are a student we may also collect:

  * Name of college/university
  * Area of college/university
  * Course name
  * Course faculty
  * Course level
  * Course end date

When you use our or our restaurants website or app to pre-order drinks or food, we collect:

  * Prefix and name
  * Contact phone number
  * Email address

When visiting our website we may collect the following information:

  * Automatically populated IP address: a public IP address is a unique number which allows a computer, group of computers or other internet connected device to browse the internet. The log file records the time and date of your visit, the pages that were requested, the referring website (if provided) and your internet browser version. This information is collected to help diagnose and manage the website, to audit the geographical make-up of users, and to establish how they have arrived at the website.
  * Cookies: for further information about Cookies and how the Royal Opera House uses them, please read the Royal Opera House [Cookie Policy](http://www.roh.org.uk/policies/cookie-usage)

Information we obtain independently from you:

Your information may be shared with us by independent organizations, for example other arts organizations that the Royal Opera House has worked with. These independent organizations will only do so when it is required to complete a contract and/or when you have indicated your consent. You should check their Privacy Notice when you provide your information to understand fully how they will process and safeguard your data.

Third Party Organizations

We may combine information you have given to us with this additional information available from external sources. This will only be done when you give permission to the relevant third party organizations to share the data they hold on you, or if the data is already publicly available.

Data Hygiene

From time to time we may screen our database against recognized data hygiene file such as National Change of Address file and cleanse our file or correct inaccurate data. We may also update inaccurate data if the information is available.

Social Media

Depending on your settings or the privacy policies for social media and messaging services like Facebook, WhatsApp or Twitter, you may give us permission to access information from those accounts or services.

Information available publicly

We may include information found in places such as Companies House and information that has been published in articles/ newspapers.

**4.       ****Why We Collect Your Personal Information and How We Use It**

The information we hold on you will be used in a number of ways. Here are the main ones: to provide a service you have requested, offer you a personalized experience and understand our audience’s needs better, inform you of events or updates you’ve asked for or contact you if we need to obtain or provide additional information (e.g. cast changes).

### Show more details

Specifically, we use your information we collect in the following ways:

**To carry out our business and to provide a service or carry out a contract with you:**

  * To fulfil ticket, merchandise, donation and membership requests.
  * Process payments. Please note that the Royal Opera House does not store any Credit Card or other payment information once the transaction has been completed.
  * Provide the best possible customer services and to help us with internal administration.
  * Contact you with important information relating to your booking or purchase, such as confirming your order, reminding you of an upcoming performance you’ve booked for or letting you know about cast changes or building works that may affect your visit.

**Where we have your consent:**

  * Send you updates via email about what’s on, offers and news or about supporting us.
  * Email you about a specific topic you’ve requested to hear more on such as cinemas, our student scheme or other projects.
  * Share your details with other arts organizations whose work you may have seen at or in collaboration with the Royal Opera House. These organisations will contact you to let you know how they collected your data and to check that you’re still happy to hear from them. You will always be able to opt out of their communications by contacting them directly.

**Where we have justifiable reason (including legal obligation and legitimate interest):**

  * Learn about your interests and preferences so that we can contact you with information that is relevant to you.
  * Help us target our marketing communications and adverts so that they’re more relevant to you.
  * Use your pseudonymised details to show you advertising on such Social Media platforms as Facebook and Instagram or via other third party advertising that may appear on other websites you use. The information shared with these platforms is pseudonymised to protect your personal data.
  * For classifying our audience into groups or segments, using booking and publicly available information. These segments help us to understand our audience better and ensure we’re sending relevant messages to each group.
  * Measure and understand how our audiences respond to a variety of marketing activity so we can ensure our activity is well targeted, relevant and effective.
  * Undertake consumer research: we may contact you to ask you to participate in consumer research either via an online or telephone survey or in person. You are under no obligation to participate in research and, should you provide any further information, the Royal Opera House will inform you how any further information will be used.
  * Analyse and continually improve the services we offer including our artistic output, our website and our other products.
  * To help us run the test version of our website that we use internally to pilot new features and ensure the smooth running of our web services.
  * To keep our database accurate and relevant, for example, using National Change of Address.
  * The use of CCTV recording equipment in and around our premises for monitoring and security purposes.
  * Undertake due diligence to detect and reduce fraud and credit risk.

**For a small number of our audience, where we want to better understand people’s engagement with the Royal Opera House and their potential interest in supporting us further:**

Before contacting a small number of individuals we may seek additional information including Royal Opera House booking and connections, business network information and publicly available information relating to: residential location, wealth and assets, family*, career, donations to other organizations (including political parties where they are made public by the individual) and hobbies and interests to create a profile of their interests and preferences. This helps us understand the background of the people who may choose to support us and helps us to make requests for gifts to those who may be able and willing to give. We may also use publicly sourced images to help identify individuals who attend our special events. For further information on applied data please see the table below.

***** This does not include information about children unless given personally by the individual concerned.

We use a number of different sources to aid us in our fundraising activities, including newspaper websites and archives, housing market websites and the electoral roll as well as official websites of companies, charities and other arts organisations. In addition to general use of the internet we also make use of company, director and shareholder information from publicly available information providers, such as the below organizations:

**Source** | **Description** | **Link**  
---|---|---  
Onesource | Company financials and directors information | <http://www.hoovers.com/>  
Lexis Nexis | Global News Archive | [www.nexis.com/ ](https://www.nexis.com/)  
Wealthmonitor | Information on company directors and shareholders | [https://app.wealthmonitor.com](https://app.wealthmonitor.com/)  
192.com | UK Electoral Roll and Directory Inquiries | <http://www.192.com/>  
Trustfunding | Database of UK Trusts and foundations grants | http://www.trustfunding.org.uk/default.aspx  
Companies House | UK Registrar of Companies | [https://beta.companieshouse.gov.uk](https://app.wealthmonitor.com/)  
  
**5.       ****How We Handle Your Information and Other Organizations**

The Royal Opera House will never share, sell, rent or trade your personal information to any third parties for marketing purposes without your prior consent. We will ask for your consent to share personal information with like-minded arts organizations whose shows you will have seen here at the Royal Opera House or in collaboration with us at another venue.

Some of our service providers may have access to your data in order to perform services on our behalf – payment processing is a good example of this. We make sure anyone who provides a service for the Royal Opera House enters into an agreement with us and meets our standards for data security. They will not use your data for anything other than the clearly defined purpose relating to the service that they are providing.

### Show more details

We may share your details with:

  * Service providers who work on behalf of the Royal Opera House for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you, for example payment processing, printers and mailing houses, marketing agencies, database services, website hosting or email delivery service.
  * Named third party organizations if you ticked the relevant opt-in box when you purchased tickets. In these instances, we may supply your personal information to that specific organization only.
  * Other organisations such as competition organizers if you choose to take part in such activities that need administration by third parties and you choose to opt in for contact from those organizations.
  * Third party data services, for example Experian, who help us to segment and understand our audience by providing additional information so that we can send the most relevant and targeted communications possible.
  * Third party advertisers (such as Facebook or Google) to help us identify customers similar to our audience or to serve relevant adverts to you on third party websites. The information shared with these advertisers is pseudonymised to protect your personal data.
  * Where required to do so (for example, if required to do so by the ‘know your donor’ principles under charity law or a court order), or when requested by the police or a regulatory or government authority investigating illegal activities.

The Royal Opera House is not responsible for the privacy notices and practices of other websites even if accessed using links from www.roh.org.uk and recommends that you check the notices of each website you visit and contact its owner or Data Protection Manager if you have any concerns or questions.

Despite all our precautions, no data transmission over the internet is 100% secure. So, we cannot guarantee the security of any information which you disclose to us and so wish to draw your attention to the fact that you do so at your own risk.

**6.       ****How We Protect Your Data**

The Royal Opera House is committed to protecting the personal information you entrust to us. We adopt robust and appropriate technologies and policies, so the information we have about you is protected from unauthorized access and improper use e.g. your online account is encrypted and our own network is protected.

### Show more details

As part of the services offered to you through the Royal Opera House website, the personal information you provide may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA). By way of example, this may happen if any of the computer servers used to host the website are located in a country outside of the EEA. If the Royal Opera House transfers your personal information outside of the EEA in this way, we will take steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be protected as outlined in this privacy notice.

The Royal Opera House may transfer your data to the USA to organizations such as Facebook, Google or Wordfly. The USA has weaker data protection laws than that of the EEA and therefore we will ensure that only organisations who are a part of the EU privacy shield initiative will handle your personal information. More details on this certification can be found at [www.privacyshield.gov/welcome](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome)

We will keep your information only for as long as is reasonably necessary for the purposes set out in this privacy notice and to fulfil our legal obligations. We will not keep more information than we need. The retention period will vary according to the purpose, for example if purchasing a ticket only, we will typically keep your data for up to ten years from the date of your last transaction whereas if you have pledged a legacy to the Royal Opera House, we will hold your details until notified by your executors. For further information about how long we will keep your information, please contact the Data Protection Manager using the contact details outlined in this notice.

If you ask us to stop sending direct marketing communications to you, we will keep the minimum amount of information (e.g. name, address or email address) to ensure we adhere with such requests.

**7.       ****Your Choices**

You should find it easy to access and amend the personal information that we hold on you, or request that we stop contacting you. It’s your data and we want to make sure you feel in control of it.

If you have an online account with us, you can amend your personal details and email contact preferences at any time. Simply sign in on the web site and access your account by selecting your name at the top of the page.

Or, if you prefer, you can contact us by phoning, emailing, or writing using our contact details below.

### Show more details

Every email we send to you will include details on how to change your communications preferences or unsubscribe from future communications.

If you would like to see what information we hold about you, you can sign into your online account and make any changes required. You can also request full details of personal information we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998, or after 25 May 2018, The General Data Protection Regulation, by contacting the Data Protection Manager. Please send a description of the information you would like to see, together with proof of your identity to [dpm@roh.org.uk](mailto:dpm@roh.org.uk)

At any time you have the right to ask the Royal Opera House to amend or stop how it uses your personal information including for marketing purposes.  
You can do this by signing in to the website and accessing your account details or if you don’t have an account or if you prefer to, you can contact us by phoning, emailing or writing using our contact details below.

You have the right to get information held about you by us corrected. If you have any concern about the accuracy of your personal data, please let us know using the below contact details.

If you would like us to remove the personal information we hold about you, please contact us using the below contact details.

You have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority, The Information Commissioner’s Office – www.ico.org.uk

By email: [dpm@roh.org.uk](mailto:dpm@roh.org.uk)  
By phone: +44 (0)20 7240 1200  
By post: Royal Opera House, Bow Street, Covent Garden, London, WC2E 9DD

**8.       ****Updates or Changes to the Privacy Notice and Further Information**

This notice was updated on 02 May 2018. It may be updated to take into account changes at the Royal Opera House or for example to reflect changes to regulation or legislation.

### Show more details

Updates to this notice will be posted on this page – please check back from time to time. We may also inform you of any changes where we hold an appropriate email address for you.

When your data is provided to us by another person (for example a recommendation) or a publicly accessible sources (such as Google) we will tell you where we obtained the information within a month of getting it.

Further information on data protection regulations and laws can be found here:

  * Data Protection: [https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public](https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/)
  * Fundraising regulator: [www.fundraisingregulator.org.uk/code-of-fundraising-practice/code-of-fundraising-practice](https://www.fundraisingregulator.org.uk/code-of-fundraising-practice/code-of-fundraising-practice/)

_  
**Notice updated on 02 May 2018**_
